<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ruby on thd.codes</title>
    <link>https://www.thd.codes/tags/ruby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ruby on thd.codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 10:32:34 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thd.codes/tags/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the Best Way to Learn Webpack?</title>
      <link>https://www.thd.codes/posts/how-to-learn-webpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 10:32:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thd.codes/posts/how-to-learn-webpack/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re feeling lost whenever you have to add some javascript library to your Rails application, this post is for you!
I see a lot of people battling against Webpacker whenever they need to add a new javascript library or have to fix a bug on the asset pipeline. I suffered from the same problems, too. I talked about why this happens on a previous post:
&amp;ldquo;Adding Bootstrap or Javascript Sprinkles to Rails breaks everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Bootstrap or Javascript Sprinkles to Rails breaks everything. What should you do?</title>
      <link>https://www.thd.codes/posts/rails-and-webpack-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 10:32:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thd.codes/posts/rails-and-webpack-pain/</guid>
      <description>Did you spend a billion hours trying to add jQuery, or Bootstrap, or Tailwind to your Rails project, but now everything on the frontend is broken?
Or worse: you can&amp;rsquo;t even tell whether the frontend is broken or not. It&amp;rsquo;s in a unkown state of brokenness.
Maybe you just want some javascript sprinkles, but Webpacker makes things so much harder and frustrating.
Do you wait until an angry customer complains about the checkout button not working anymore to know which page to fix?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How should I change production data on a new Rails application?</title>
      <link>https://www.thd.codes/posts/rails-data-migrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 13:32:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thd.codes/posts/rails-data-migrations/</guid>
      <description>You need to change production data. You know that doing it manually is unsafe and will definetely cause lots of trouble, like corrupting all you customer&amp;rsquo;s data.
How else should you do it?
You might be spending a lot of time asking yourself these questions:
 Is there a proper rails way to change data in production? Should I run data and schema modifications in one database migration? Should I run rake scripts in production to modify data?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collatz Conjecture</title>
      <link>https://www.thd.codes/posts/collatz-conjecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 15:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thd.codes/posts/collatz-conjecture/</guid>
      <description>The Collatz Conjecture is a simple mathematical problem that still has no formal proof. So it&amp;rsquo;s an open problem.
This is how it works:
Choose any positive integer x. While x &amp;gt; 0, do: if x is even, divide it by 2 (x = x/2) if x is odd, multiply it by 3 and add 1 (x = 3x + 1) The Collatz Conjecture states that no matter what value of x you start with, the sequence will always reach x = 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
