<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ruby on rails on thd.codes</title>
    <link>https://www.thd.codes/tags/ruby-on-rails/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ruby on rails on thd.codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 10:13:18 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thd.codes/tags/ruby-on-rails/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Examples on How to Remove Sprockets From a Rails Application</title>
      <link>https://www.thd.codes/posts/how-to-remove-sprockets-from-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 10:13:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thd.codes/posts/how-to-remove-sprockets-from-rails/</guid>
      <description>You want to add bootstrap, or jquery, or react, or any other javascript library/tool/framework the cool kids are using now to your Rails App. 🕶️
You search for a tutorial. First, they tell you to import some file on javascript/application.js.
Later, you come accross another tutorial that tells you to use Webpacker.
Eventually, you realize that Rails 6 comes both with Sprockets AND Webpacker set up by default. 🤯
In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know, Sprockets and Webpacker are two completely different ways to compile and serve static assets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to pick your first Rails Issue and start contributing to Open-Source</title>
      <link>https://www.thd.codes/posts/picking-a-rails-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 13:52:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thd.codes/posts/picking-a-rails-issue/</guid>
      <description>Did you always want to help an open-source project like Ruby on Rails, but never got started?
Many people have the interest of contributing to open-source, myself included. I&amp;rsquo;ve done a couple of small contributions, but nothing fancy.
It&amp;rsquo;s a little intimidating, right? You&amp;rsquo;re not part of the group of contributors and you don&amp;rsquo;t really know where to start. You see 800 open issues, but which one should you pick?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How should I change production data on a new Rails application?</title>
      <link>https://www.thd.codes/posts/rails-data-migrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 13:32:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thd.codes/posts/rails-data-migrations/</guid>
      <description>You need to change production data. You know that doing it manually is unsafe and will definetely cause lots of trouble, like corrupting all you customer&amp;rsquo;s data.
How else should you do it?
You might be spending a lot of time asking yourself these questions:
 Is there a proper rails way to change data in production? Should I run data and schema modifications in one database migration? Should I run rake scripts in production to modify data?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
